[Music]
the war the revolutionary war the
british are coming
let's do this
[Music]
hello
hello i'm craig astad
and today
we're going to talk about george
washington crossing the delaware river
on christmas day
so it's the end of the year 1776 the
continental army is camped out on the
shores of the delaware river in
pennsylvania george washington is like
the continental army is
it seems hopeless
across the river in trenton new jersey
is the hessians the hessians are german
mercenary soldiers for the british
empire and like hey man we're cool
and we're making money
on
december 23rd washington brings general
hugh mercer who's a scottish general and
gener and captain alexander hamilton
george rogers like look we have to
attack the british on christmas night
they're gonna be drunk they're gonna be
burping
you know eating that's the night
that the least expected so we get we
have to move we gotta go it's a surprise
attack so
mercer's like you know he's the scottish
guy he's like you know we don't have
munitions
i don't even know what i can do it think
about sean connery
off
mercer's like well we can't do this now
we we don't have the provisions
and alexander hamilton's point of view
is hey that's exactly why we need to
attack because the hessians have
infinite musician musicians they have
infinite
infinite infinite munitions and we can
capture all that
so
all right well this is what's going down
we got 5 000 troops we're gonna cross
the river it's like 300 yards wide
all right yeah we have to go full force
on attack which is fighting against the
british with their hired
hessian german
army
so the germans so
the germans
all right so it's a german christmas
december 25th
1776. they're all celebrating
it's this is celebration let's
have sausages and sauerkrauts
they're being festive they're drinking
eggnog that's exactly what the germans
were doing
back to the three platoons they all set
sail across the delaware river mercers
washington hamilton
mercer it's it's it's too much snow too
much ice you have to back off jesus told
me so
so they back off
you know hamilton's balls the walk we
got to get across there man we got to
help hamilton but we got to help
washington
can't do it man it's too much snow too
much ice too much it's too cold
washington says we're getting across
this river dude
everyone knows the story from the
painting the painting is like a pretty
picture of this it was a lot more grimy
and dirty than painting it's the winds
man blowing 60 70 miles an hour little
tiny icebergs smashing up against these
primitive boats that are made out of
cheap pine wood that's been mailed
nailed together with garbage
nails just horrible
some of the soldiers have towels on
their feet they don't have shoes and
they're thinking hey
man this is christmas i should be eating
gingerbread man washington's like hey
man this is the birth of our nation
the this is the birth of our nation i
mean it really is
hey let me have a drink
they roll up upon the shore trenton new
jersey george washington looks at the
sun and he's like hey
we're late let's
let's do this
washington and his soldiers march into
the fort of trenton and sure as
catch the entire hessian military off
guard they start attacking the hessians
hey merry christmas they're
not met with much resistance they're
like well wait we need to fight but
we're kind of drunk and we're kind of
up
like mistletoe and jingle bells
so by the time the battle was over
washington had captured over a thousand
hessians and only four continental army
troops had died and then they looked
there's all these supplies and then in
the corner there's a pile of rum
they all start pounding rum getting
drunk so when they took these
hessian soldiers back across the river
after capturing them a lot of them were
drunk just putting them on boats and
people are like falling off face
trying to get it's just fun
[Music]
so this is the first major victory for
george washington and his continental
army and it made an announcement to the
entire world that hey
this continental army is a force to be
reckoned with you can't you can't
underestimate that
[Music]
hi
this story will be about wilhelm very
freezing down here
i'm going to tell you a story about
general von stupen
it's the american revolution washington
troops are freezing to death they said
washington you don't know what you're
doing everybody around us is dying they
don't have anything to eat they are
freezing cold what are you going to do
washington says i'm going to talk to my
buddy ben franklin
because i don't even know about it
franklin was just partying in fairs it's
very weird
franklin learns of this prussian war
general von strueben he was trained by
the king of prussia ben franklin says
hey vince joyben why don't you come to
california
uh
no
ben franklin says why don't you come
to america and fight for us and von
steuben's like
look i already got kicked out of prussia
for being gay
i'm okay here in paris
it's okay to be gay in paris
and paris is like
not okay to be gay in paris we're about
to kick you out and vince schuman says
check please
sylvan soyman shows up with cooks and
butlers he's dressed to the nines he's
wearing furs he's got a dog and he says
hey i'm von steuben
he looks at all of general washington
soldiers
and he says look at this group of dogs
they're dying they're starving they have
no ammunition no love the soldiers were
like i don't like this guy george
wallace says no no give him a chance
give him a chance give him a chance and
find steuben's like
i am gonna whip you guys into shape new
coach is in town vine stupid starts
training the soldiers
running through the rinks he's
stretching them through the stretchers
he's yelling at them and prussian then
they go what's he saying washington is
like oh boy the guy doesn't even speak
english so he says blah blah blah blah
what are we going to do
but guess what
young captain shows up ben walker
he says i can understand all the blah
blah i speak oppression and i can help
the americans understand him my student
turns over his shoulder and sees
the most handsome american he's seen so
far still is into blondes this guy is
platinum blocked
beautiful cheek bones puffy lips
benjamin walker says i will be
your guide and uh they become buzz
but
they have this this
this training
montage
so benjamin walker ends up being exactly
what they needed he helps him with the
troops my stupid starts teaching him
things he's like these are knives you
can use it to stab people and they're
like ah that's a great idea teach them
how to clean their teeth teach them how
to clean their bodies so they don't get
disease people are like we're just
trying to win a war man and he's like
this is how you win a war
they start training harder and then he
says ben walker yell at them in english
and that guy says more squats more
squats come on
he literally turn he turned
he turned the army into better
do you know any drinking games
oh yeah
i was just thinking is there any way we
could take this shot oh what's that you
guys drink
oh wait
so
it's the battle springtime no it's
battle hill
no
it's the battle of baron hill
these terrified kids are just crushing
it
as troops start feeding battle after a
battle using the attaches of violent
stubborn to use their bayonets they got
all clean teeth
and they won the war
washington said von steuben you live
with washington
i'm sorry
ben walker
washington said
i'm gonna give you a house to live in
and i want you to live with that guy ben
benoit
that guy
i will grant you the most beautiful love
ever
so the army used von steuben's tactics
for 100 years they called the blue the
blue book that that's why we're here
safe
so von steuben saved the world
hello
today we are going to talk about
benedict
arnold
benedict arnold was a general in the
american revolution he's a hero of
saratoga but the continental congress
promoted five other generals and not
benedict arnold
benedict arnold was very uh bummed out
by that so he goes to philadelphia
there's a young woman peggy shippen who
is the it girl of philadelphia peggy was
like i'm hilarious i'm british and i'm
the most beautiful person that anyone's
ever seen
she has a suitor named john andre but
benedict sees her and just falls crazy
in love with her and tells her he's
better with you this is not an exact
quote it's better you were so great i
love you so much you're so great so she
marries benedict arnold who i believe
she also loved
oh god what i just realized that i was
being filmed
oh my god so anyway peggy says
sweetheart you deserve to be backed by
the government that you belong to
you know
the british
would appreciate you they would love you
also
my family's british benedict's like no
no
no no i'm not gonna i'm not gonna defect
to the british side that's insane george
washington is my daddy kind of
peggy says
look i have a friend
in the british army john andre
benedict's like looks like a your
ex-boyfriend peggy's like well i mean
benedict if you really want to be with
me be more confident and benedict's like
yeah
yeah i am going to betray the united
states because
i love you and i'm going to prove to you
that i am not jealous
and makes
love to his wife and she's like i love
it i love being a spy this is so great
because i love drama and peggy shippen
like what an adventure she's sheltered
and titled
i have this whole imaginary chorus of
women that are like don't say i was like
but she was a
she was bad
peggy says you write me letters i'm
going to pass them on to
john andre so benedict writes letters
which are
really passionate they're like uh peggy
i love that that i get to do with you
because he knows that john andre is
going to get them also the continental
army is going to west point
also i love you and i love you i love
you so they're passing letters back and
forth back and forth back and forth and
eventually benedict tells john andre
okay i'm going to give you the
information on how to attack us
i'll tell you everything also i'm going
to invite george washington to my house
so you can take them if you want like
his friend
love
yeah sucks sucks so much so
they meet behind american lines and
benedict takes out all these maps and
says okay
if you're going to attack
you need to attack this way and they're
signed by benedict arnold which i don't
understand why he would do that so john
andre starts headed home he doesn't get
very far before he encounters three men
they're like okay you have a red coat
and you have a british accent we're
going to search you down andre's like
he has these maps
and they realize that
benedict arnold has become a traitor
so benedict says to peggy
babe
we've been found out and she's like you
just you get out of here like i'll deal
with it on this end meanwhile george
washington is walking up to their house
george washington head of
life
the head of the entire continental army
is like i'm gonna have breakfast with uh
peggy and benedict my favorite people in
the whole world he gets these papers
that benedict arnold betrayed him and he
very famously says
whom do we trust now
i'm too drunk um
he goes to the house peggy meanwhile
rips off half of her clothes she's
holding her six-month-old peggy says
you are sent here to kill my baby baby
killer you're here to kill my baby and
he's like oh my gosh you're crazy you're
so good no
he's just like a woman with her hysteria
she's crazy right now but she's
absolutely i can say without a doubt
that she is innocent
she was she was she was brilliant she
was great she wasn't great she was bad
anyway benedict arnold joins the british
he's like hey i was american five
minutes ago and now i'm british let's do
this and they were like no we don't we
don't trust you because you're this
traitor
get out of here and he is shunned by
everyone and then he was this like
limping
sad man and before he died he said to
peggy take out my
continental uniform and she put it on
him and he said i i regret ever wearing
any other
uniform and he died he died in his
american uniform
you know what's really funny about being
drunk is that
you really feel like you're doing all
the important things that you needed to
do
right
today we're going to talk about sybil
lonning
ludington
who did the midnight ride
that
you haven't heard about but you will
right
so it's early on in the revolution and
the british are tearing through the
colonies blah blah
sybil ludington just had her 16th
birthday her dad henry luddington is the
head of the local militia fending off
the british so on this particular night
she's tucking in her brothers and
sisters and all of a sudden
there's a knock on the door
this man is at the door
oh my god he's so out of breath the
british are burning danbury connecticut
okay okay so henry luddington is like i
need to
go knock on every door get our militia
and save our country
well here's the thing though i have to
stay here to like rally the troops and
make the plan it's not like you can send
an evite out so who's gonna
do it
i'll do it
comes a peep from the night
hey
[Music]
blah blah
i got it sybil comes pee pee peeping
down the night and her dad's like she's
16 years old she's a girl it's a
hard ass night outside
it's 40
miles
well we don't have a better option so
yeah we're gonna let her do it
she sets out into the night so guess
what happens
it starts raining well
snap
it's raining it's like windy trails and
boulders she grabs a stick and she's
chat jack whacking it on all the doors
she passes by
she's like the british are coming
if you
the british are coming you have to
follow me
come back to the lottington and if
you're not coming then you're another
go go go
this is the moment where i'm like oh i
really am drunk
so she rounds a corner and suddenly
this ass
jumps out of the bushes
stop your horse
you know give me your purse or whatever
she's like all i have is this stick so
man just flap flap flap fluff
flaps him in the neck
you know do you know what i'm saying
yeah classic flap in the neck yeah
as it came out it sounded weird but you
know what i mean
she just lifts him up keeps going don't
have time
have to round up militiamen she gets to
every house on the route spread out over
miles
people follow her back to henry
luddington's home and he is like oh my
goodness you did it let's go let's go
get these ass let's make it happen
damn it
i was doing such a good job
okay so here comes henry luddington's
militia they beat back the british and
they were like this is the deal and
there you go and there you stay and
there you went
and bye bye bye charlie
so a couple weeks go by
holy sh
life is back to normal
a knock on the door and standing at the
door
is george
washington
and he is like i'm here to give
congratulations to the
best effort i've seen
ever
henry luddington is like oh you're
welcome sir and george washington's like
stand aside
am here to see sybil ludington
who did that
amazing ride sybil from the woodwork
comes out oh
yes sir
thank you sir
i don't know why in that
part she had a british accent but he was
like
you
are the best you didn't
i can't ask for a better spirit of force
from anyone
and
huzzah
and that's
yeah
how's that
20 miles is what paul revere wrote and
then double it and that's what sybil
ludington did which is 40 miles that's
the whole thing period end of history
and that's the deal
and
that's
the
hello i'm paget brewster and today we
will be discussing deborah sampson the
first woman to take a bullet for america
cheers
okay in plympton massachusetts deborah
sampson becomes an indentured servant to
jeremiah thomas lucky for her
jeremiah was a
fierce patriot and taught her how to do
everything that other girls weren't
being taught
and so she grows up to be an incredible
badass
so she's thinking what am i going to be
i want adventure i want to serve my
country so
i think
i think i want
yeah i want to fight in the
revolutionary war
so
she sews
a men's outfit she's like i'm gonna make
trousers
or britches
trouser britches
and a waistcoat
and uh what's a waistcoat waistcoat i
think is a
vest
coat
it's just a waste
what it's just a waste
you're approaching bad humor but you're
not a dad
how do you know oh
do you have a baby
okay
so she sews everything up cuts her hair
off she also has to take gauze and strap
her
boobs down was she like oh my gosh
what was she like oh my gosh
oh my gosh
holy sh i'm just embracing my fatherhood
but yeah
so deborah sampson looks at this young
man and says
my name is robert
and robert sherlock
and they accept her
him
into george washington's army
and she develops an incredible
reputation
all the other soldiers are saying holy
this robert shirtless
he's a badass he's right out in front
he's the fastest runner in the army but
at terrytown
in the middle of the revolutionary war
robert deborah is fighting the british
and out of the blue
blammo she gets shot in the thigh with a
musket ball
deborah samson is historically the first
woman to take a bullet for america the
other soldiers are like dude bobby bubby
sherliff you okay
but she has to keep her identity safe so
she's like
yep got this got this i'm good you're
cool i'm cool
that voice is hard
okay
this is where it gets crazy she slinks
off to the woods like
this
i cannot go to the hospital
i cannot let anyone find out that i'm a
woman
she takes out a pen knife
jabs it into her thigh
oh
gotta dig out this musket ball digs
it out she's like well
i can sew
sews it up
and says america
i care about you so much
oh i'm gonna cry i don't want to cry
let it out you can cry what stuff
i'm talking to america
okay
unfortunately deborah gets
crazy fifa sick
like
good
can't butt burp
she is hospitalized the one thing she's
been trying to avoid
so dr barnabas benny is like okay here's
the soldier kind of a badass soldier all
right i'll see what's wrong takes off
robert shirtless clothing what
there's
like
binding on the chest maybe there's
something wrong under here it cuts it
open
boobs
and he
goes
[Music]
okay
it's so crazy how it seems so easy when
you're
so bird to tell a story
wait where was i
wait i know
so he takes care of her for seven months
and she says thank you for taking care
of me
if there's anything i can do to repay
your kindness please let me know
and he says
actually
will you do me a favor and take a letter
to my friend general john patterson
so
she delivers the letter to john
patterson
general says thank you
young lady
he
reads this letter
looks at her and says
private
robert shirtless
are you
a woman
pretending to be a man
to be a soldier
and she says general
i only lied because i wanted to serve my
country
please don't send me to jail and he says
young lady i think what you've done
is better and braver
and stronger
than
so many men
and i'm going to give you a dishonorable
i'm going to give you a sorry i'm going
to give you an honorable discharge
and that paul revere the
superstar of the american revolution is
like i'm a big american hero but i think
you're the babe
it's incredible that more than 200 years
ago
this woman
wanted to make a difference
so she becomes this cross-dressing
bullet-digging badass
who fought her balls off
lol no pun intended
who's the dad joke now
the war the revolutionary war burr and
hamilton start their respective war
careers
and burr has a really distinguished war
career um like kills a lot of british
dudes has an amazing sort of run
meanwhile george washington asks
hamilton hey be my aide to kemp aide de
camp is like a fancy word for secretary
nah nah nah i'm good i want to fight i
want to fight because that's how i'm
going to rise up washington's like
mother
like come work for me it's paperwork
sure but you're going to be at the
center of the action you're gonna be in
the guy in with the guy who knows best
and hamilton does his political calculus
and says okay
so hamilton writes his letters hamilton
writes letters to congress this whole
time all hamilton wants is a command
hamilton's just sort of tugging on his
sleeve being like
can i fight can i can you just give me
like a bunch of dudes and like i promise
i'll be so good at this and washington's
like no just
stay in the camp but they go through
some of the toughest trials of the war
together it's it's hamilton and
washington
and then hamilton finally goes i quit
i'm out and washington aware of what a
sort of gifted
but troubled kid hamilton is it says all
right you're gonna lead these troops to
do this very specific thing in the
battle of yorktown
hopefully this is our last battle anyway
but like you will be able to say you led
a command and so
hamilton goes into it like with
ridiculous gusto um he's like he she's
like jumping ahead of everyone being
like ah we're at war wow like like he's
like showboating
okay
i'ma lean forward arrow good
oh i'm drunk you feel okay
i'm giggly and
there's gaps in my memory i'm sorry
already okay so uh let's get back
so yorktown
we won well now we've got to form a
country
um they all ask him hey come be part of
the constitutional convention
so we're figuring out
how the american system is going to work
the constitutional convention this is
the room where they're deciding what the
shape of our government should be
they're hashing it out and hamilton
speaks for six hours but some of the
things he pitched would haunt him the
rest of his career he pitched maybe
president for life
maybe
uh
we inherit
positions
that's terrible this guy just
wants to bring back the british
those whispers are from the perspectives
of
people who don't like him um but anyway
we adopt the system that we adopt and
hamilton becomes its most ardent
defender
[Music]
you